NAA Records 5775
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Membership Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  List of the committee members (1965); Letter regarding two applicants and expressing concern as to their acceptability, one thought to be a union attorney (Harry Galfand), the other a management consultant (Cy Ching) (1966); Letter concerning applicant Cy Ching, relates receipt of positive comments and suggests his resume be sent to the membership (1965); Letter to president from committee chair relating these recommendations: that Cy Ching be admitted under Section 2B, that a list of applicants be admitted, that several applicants be deferred, and that several applicants be held or processed. Letter also expresses concern over admission standards for state board members (1965); Letter requesting application materials, and cover letter sent with such materials (1966); Biographical resumes of applicants, also, blank comment forms (1965); Cover letter with biographical resumes of applicants, transferring resumes for duplication and circularization to the membership (1965); Letter relating regret that Mrs. Holdridge (a secretary) will not attend the annual meeting (1965); Cover letter to check for Eastern Airlines, letter also advises that Cy Ching's resume be circulated to the membership (1965); Invoice for envelopes (1965); Letter concerning application of Cy Ching, unanimously endorsed by committee, question as to whether or not it is necessary to circulate his resume to the membership (1965); Letter requesting check for airline tickets for a secretary and announcing the next committee meeting (1965); Letter thanking for reply to an inquiry (no elaboration) and noting change of address (1965); Letter relating change of address, and serving as a cover letter to dues payment (1965); Cover letter to dues payment and Academy reply (1965); correspondence regarding Ted Tsukiyama's request for application materials; Correspondence regarding Cy Ching's application for membership, some discussion of the possibility of amending the constitution to include "a special category of honorary membership" for "a person of real distinction, a labor relations expert and labor dispute `neutral'" (1965); Letter from nominating committee to membership announcing the nominations for new officers (1965); Letter from new member thanking for his acceptance, and serving as a cover letter to his dues payment (1965); Letters requesting dues payments (1965); Cover letter to letter concerning the Board's rejection of George F. Hayes (1965); Academy reply to, and letter from a would-be arbitrator desiring information on the academy, includes two resumes (1965); Letter from a new member thanking for his admission (1965); Letter to member requesting the signed affirmation of dues payment (1965); correspondence concerning the transfer of applicants files, accepted, deferred, or otherwise; Letter making arrangements for new members, includes: inscription of certificates of membership, sending of insurance material, making up of address plates, and the sending of the current Volume of Proceedings (1965); List of new members and their addresses (1965); Letter notifying applicants of their acceptance, with list of enclosures (1965); Material concerning actions of the Board of Governors at the 9/18/65 meeting, includes: the list of new members, the list of rejected applicants, and the list of applications still under consideration. Also mentioned is making Cyrus Ching a "Special Permanent Honorary Guest:, and the raising of the issue of charitable or scholarship funds in honor of deceased members (1965); Letter extending best wishes to a member who was in an accident (1965); Letter requesting that application materials be sent to four men and the cover letters sent with such materials (1965); Letter regarding an injured member's request for the necessary forms to enter a claim (1965); Letter requesting a member sign and return his dues affirmation (1965); Form letter announcing the next Board of Governors meeting, listing the agenda, and inquiring if member will attend (1965); Cover letter returning a check and signed affirmation statement to new member, member had already paid dues, affirmation statement returned for member's records (1965); Biographical resumes and comment sheets (1965); Letter relating the transfer of some correspondence, noting that the committee's proposed policy statement will be presented at the Board of Governors meeting, and noting that the committee's recommendations with respect to the membership will be considered (1965); Sympathy letter sent to the widow of Carl R. Schedler (1965); Cover letter to dues check and signed affirmation (1965); Letter to member stating that his dues check was received and deposited, also request from member that this be checked (1965); Letter requesting application materials, and cover letter sent with such materials (1965); Letter concerning Academy member Alec Frey's refusal to sign the affirmation statement (1965); Cover letter transferring the application of, and letter praising Nathan Cayton (1965); Letter concerning, and actual letter from Alexander Frey refusing to sign the affirmation statement (1965); Letter returning dues statement to member for signature (1965); Letter which accompanied a member's dues check and signed affirmation statement (1965); Letter from applicant inquiring as to the status of his application and Academy reply explaining the process and directing further inquiries to the committee chairman (1965); Letters accompanying and apologizing for late dues checks (1965); Letter to president informing him of the death of member Carl Schedler and suggesting he send a note of sympathy to the family (1965); Letters to members informing them they have not sent in their dues or affirmation statements (1965); Bill from Beaux Arts Studios for one Academy Certificate (1965); Letter requesting application materials, and cover letters sent with such materials (1965); Letter from member thanking for the return of his check (1965); Letter thanking for sending of application forms, and noting they were filled out and sent in (1965); Letter from member requesting an application be sent to Abner Brodie, included is a partial list of Brodie's arbitration cases (1965); Letter relating the committee's policy as to full-time assistants to permanent chairman (1965); Letter to applicant notifying receipt of the completed form (1965); Letter from member requesting that application materials be sent to William P. Murphy and cover letter sent with such materials (1965); Letter from applicant noting that his application has been completed and sent in, also inquires if another copy is needed. Also, letter from secretary to committee stating he did not realize an application was already filed when the forms were sent out (1965); Letter from member requesting application materials be sent to Rankin M. Gibson, also cover letter sent with such materials (1965); Cover letter to member returning extra check and dues statement (1965); Correspondence regarding the committee chairmen's secretary, and the proposal that she be invited to the annual meeting expenses to be paid by the Academy as a token of appreciation for her work for the Academy (1965); Letter requesting application materials, and cover letter sent with such materials (1965); Letter to member returning dues check since member's dues had been waived (1965); Letter concerning an effort to get discount privileges with Hertz or Avis (1965); Letter to applicant David M. Helfeld informing him of his acceptance into the Academy and appointing him to the Arrangements Committee and the Program Committee (1965); Letter making arrangements for acceptance of David M. Helfeld, includes: sending of the current Volume of Proceedings, inscription of a Certificate of Membership, and sending of insurance material (1965); Letter requesting more copies of "Statements of Academy Purposes and Aims" and "Policy Relative to Membership" (1965); Letters requesting application materials and cover letters sent with such materials (1965); Letter of regret to resigning member (1965); Sympathy letter to Mrs. Harold T. Dworet concerning the recent death of her husband (1965); Correspondence regarding the signing of the membership certificates (1965); Letter concerning Frank P. Douglass' failure to sign affirmation statement, unable to do so due to sickness (1965); Letter relating the death of member Harold Dworet (1965); Letter from member endorsing applicant David M. Helfeld, also his biographical resume which was sent out to the membership, also blank comment sheet (1965); Letter staffing the committee (1965); Letter sent out with dues statements (for signature of affirmation statement, not to get dues) to members whose dues payment has been waived (1965); List of new members and their addresses (1965); Letters sent out to new members notifying them of their acceptance, also serving as a cover letter to the usual materials sent to new members (1965); Correspondence making arrangements for new members, includes: inscription of Certificates of Membership, making up of address plates, and the sending of insurance material (1965); Letter serving as a cover letter to transferred "files" (1965); Letter relating to members the reports being distributed to those who missed the annual meeting (1965); Letter appointing chairman of the committee; Cover letter to application materials sent to Leo W. Walsh (1965); Reply to an invitation from Charles S. Rhyme to the World Peace Through Law Center conference, was sent with a copy of the membership directory suggesting Mr. Rhyme write individual members, since the Academy as a whole could not become involved (1965); Letters to Harry Abrahams wishing him a speedy recovery from his illness (1965); Cover letter to application forms sent to Leon Herman for reapplication (1965); Cover letter to membership directory sent to Joseph J. Smith in response to his request for information about the Academy's activities and membership requirements (1965); Excerpt from Jan. 26, 1965 Board Minutes. The committee's section lists accepted applicants, one applicant tabled for further investigation, and one for further consideration, also raises the issue of assistants in an umpire system (1965); Letter relating to secretary that committee chairman ordered envelopes from his office and that the bill is enclosed (1965); Letter sent to membership announcing the annual meeting and requesting information such as, whether or not they plan to attend, if their wife is coming, etc. (1965); Cover letter, and actual (blank) Arbitration Survey Committee Questionnaire sent out to membership for completion and return (1965).
- Membership Committee, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  List of committee members; Request from member that application materials be sent to Roy R. Ray, and cover letter sent with such materials (1964); Biographical resumes of applicants with mostly blank comment forms, except for "rejected" written nest to Irving R. Markowitz's resume (1964); Letter transferring resumes of applicants (attached) to secretary for distribution to membership (1964); Letters transferring membership certificates for signing (1964); Letter arranging for the inscription of Certificates of Membership for new members (1964); Correspondence regarding member Glenn A. Bowers' request to resign from membership since he is retiring (1964); Letters from new members thanking for their admittance (1964); Request for sending of application materials, and cover letters sent with such materials (1964); Letter to John A. Hogan noting his failure to pay dues and then thanking for such payment (1964); Letters requesting application materials, and cover letters sent with such materials (1964); Letter from member requesting blank application forms to give to two local arbitrators, also reply from secretary of the Academy that names be sent to him since other materials need to be sent with the forms (1964); Letters to new members notifying them of their acceptance and serving as a cover letter for the usual materials (1964); Correspondence making arrangement's for new members, includes: sending of insurance material, sending of the volume, Labor Arbitration - Perspectives and Problems; inscription of certificates of membership, and making up of address plates (1964); List of new members and their addresses (1964); Letter transferring files of new members to the secretary (1964); Copy of telegram sent to committee chairman requesting the transfer of new members' files to the secretary (1964); Letter to Harry Abrahams wishing him a "speedy and full recovery" from his illness (1964); Letters sent to members who have not paid their dues (1964); Information "For Secretary Miller's Report To October 31, 1964 Board Meeting", includes membership numbers and dues payment information (1964); Letter relating Gerald Somers inability to attend the annual meeting (1964); Letter relating the death of member Robert Hasley Wettach (1964); Letter from member Lawrence E. Seibel expressing his desire for "a place on the agenda to discuss some policy matters with the Membership Committee" (1964); Letter from the Academy to Mrs. Alpha Wettach expressing sympathies in regards to her husband's death (1964); Request from a member to send application materials to George Moscowitz, also includes the cover letter sent with such materials (1964); Letter noting the death of Academy member Robert H. Wettach, includes an obituary (1964); Biographical resumes of applicants and blank comment forms (1964); Letters requesting application materials and cover letters sent with such materials (1964); Letter from John P. McGury requesting his application be reconsidered, includes a list of cases done since he last applied (1964); Letter from Academy to Mrs. Dorothy B. Clements expressing sympathies in regard to her husband's death, also includes letters noting this Members death, and giving the address of Mrs. Clements (1964); Cover letter for and notice of "Appointments and Committee Rosters 1964-1965" (1964); Correspondence regarding paper that was ordered (1964); Cover letter transferring an application (1964); Copy of letter originally on back of dues statement, letter relates member's intent to retire (1964); Letter asking for more stationary (1964); Blank copy of application form, new form introduced in 1964, accompanying letter notes that these are folded wrong, at the side rather than at the top (1964); Letter requesting application materials and cover letter sent with such materials (1964); Letter transferring signed membership certificates; Request from member for blank application forms for distribution, also Academy reply which suggests the member send in the names of the interested arbitrators to facilitate the sending of the other application materials (1964); Letter arranging that applicant August Lanna be sent the application materials (1964); Letter notifying member Glenn A. Bowers that he has not yet paid his dues (1964); Letter transferring membership certificates to the president for signing (1964); Letter requesting application materials and cover letter sent with such materials (1964); "Recommended Changes In The Application For Membership" (1964); List of the names and addresses of the new members (1964); Letter seemingly requesting application materials and cover letter sent with such materials (1964); Letter from member requesting blank application forms, also, the Academy secretary's reply which serves as a cover letter to the forms, and suggests that potential applicants be referred to the secretary (1964); letter concerning Quentin C. Vines' dues payment, or lack thereof, also raises possibility that he will request a dues waiver (1964); Request from a member to resign from the Academy, reply states that he will be considered for a dues waiver (1964); Letter relating idea for a closed cocktail party for new members only at the end of the General Business Meeting at the annual Meeting (1964); Letters sent to new members informing them of their acceptance and serving as a cover letter to the usual materials (1964); Letter making arrangements for new members, includes: making up of address plates, inscription of Certificates of Membership, sending of insurance material, and sending of current Volume of Proceedings (1964); Letter replying to draft for new application forms, offers several suggestions for improvement (1964); Letter transferring files of approved applicants, also served as a cover letter for a list of names to be added to the permanent guest list (1964); Cover letters sent with application materials (1964); Cover letter to copies of "Policy Relative to Membership" and "Statement of Academy Purposes and Aims" (1964); List of new members names and addresses (1964); Excerpt from Board minutes relative to the committee, includes: a list of the accepted members, and the changes in the application form (1964).
- Membership Committee, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  Request for application from Frank W. McCulloch, who plans to step down from his position as NLRB Chairman soon, also an internal Academy letter with suggestions as to how to handle the situation since Mr. McCulloch has no actual arbitration experience (1970); Letter informing applicant Anthony V. Sinicropi that he does not have a substantial enough case load for acceptance, suggest he reapply later, after he gets more experience (1970);Letter to applicant Charles J. Morris suggesting that he delay his application for membership until he gains more experience, a more substantial case load (1970); Letter from non-member requesting reprints of Academy lectures on arbitration (1970); Letter to committee members announcing the next meeting (1970); Biographical resumes of applicants (1970); Letter to applicant Harry F. Stark notifying him that the committee is holding off on deciding on his application until the end of the year, also asks for a list, around that time, of any additional cases (1970); Letter to applicant Walter H. Allman requesting more information if he still wants to apply (1970); Letter to applicant J. Thomas Rimer, Jr. notifying him that he should reapply in the future since at the present time his arbitration experience is too far in the past, and currently he seems to be a management spokesperson (1970); Letter from member in support of denied applicant Anthony Sinicropi, also, secretary's reply which states that the applicant was denied due to insufficient experience and also states that the member's letter would be passed on to the committee (1970); Draft and final letter sent to applicant Frank W. McCulloch, former NLRB Chairman, the letter suggests that he delay his application until he gets more experience, it also notifies him that Rolf Valtin will be in touch with him to discuss the matter, and future alternatives (1970); Correspondence in relation to the matter of Frank W. Mc Culloch's inquiry about membership in the Academy (1970); Letter concerning the application of Howard D. Brown, suggests that he was not accepted due to lack of experience, he has only been an arbitrator for two years (1970); Biographical resumes and blank comment forms, also includes a handwritten letter transferring these from the committee chairman to the secretary (1970); Cover letter to several copies of the Academy's "Statement Of Policy Relative To Membership" sent to Justo Pastor Rivera (1970); Cover letter to, and biographical resumes of applicants (1970); Letter to applicant Berwyn F. Hanley from committee chairman suggesting he withdraw his application on the basis of insufficient acceptability since all of his cases except one are through a state agency (1970); Letter to applicant Robert L. Gibson denying acceptance on the basis of his representational work (1970); Letter to applicant Lewis B. Kaden suggesting he withdraw his application on the basis of inexperience, and the fact that he still does some representational work (1970); Letter to applicant Harry F. Stark suggesting he withdraw his application and apply at a later date when he has more solidly established himself as an arbitrator (1970).
- Membership Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  Handwritten draft of letter to members who have not replied to the address inquiry for the membership directory (1968?); List of names and addresses of new members (1967).
- Membership Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  Reply to a letter from Herbert Schmertz in which he expressed his desire to withdraw from membership in the Academy. The reply notes that his dues will be reimbursed, and that it is hoped he will continue to be interested in the Academy (1966); Letters requesting application materials and cover letters sent with such materials (1966); Letter, with bills attached, requesting checks to cover some of the committee's expenses (1966); Letter to member Herbert Schmertz suggesting he withdraw from membership in light of his appointment to an industry post (1966); Letter to member Lloyd H. Bailer in reply to his letter expressing concern over the minimal information present in the biographical resumes; letter explains the purpose of the resumes, but state that his recommendations will be considered (1966); Letter to applicant Hillard Kreimer stating that his application has been received (1966); Letter reminding that action needs to be taken on Herbert Schmertz's withdrawal request (1966); Letter from applicant noting that his application has been sent in (1966); Letter requesting application materials, and cover letter sent with such materials (1966); Letter noting that the stationary finally arrived (1966); Note written by member Eugene Russell requesting that his membership be discontinued (1966); Biographical resumes of applicants and blank comment sheets (1966); List of "Appointments and Committee Rosters" (1966); Letter that accompanied the transfer of some applicants' files (1966); Letter requesting application materials, and cover letter sent with such materials (1966); Correspondence as to the whereabouts of the stationary shipment (1966); correspondence regarding, and actual letter (from Lawrence E. Seibel) stating the policy of the membership committee during Seibel's term (1966); Letter inquiring about application procedure and Academy reply which explains it (1966); Letter requesting application materials and cover letter sent with such materials (1966); Sympathy letter sent to wife of deceased member Z. Clark Dickinson (1966); Letter accompanying dues check of member Jay Murphy; Letter noting death of member Z. Clark Dickinson (1966); Letter requesting application materials and cover letter sent with such materials (1966); Letter reminding committee chairman that biographical resumes must be submitted to members 30 days prior to any action on them by the Board of Governors (1966); Letter from the committee chairman to the secretary stating that the committee probably will not have anything to report by the time of the spring meeting (1966); Letter requesting application materials, and cover letter sent with such materials (1966); Correspondence regarding the death of member Joe Stashower and transferring a check to pay for the floral arrangement sent to his funeral (1966); Dues statement of Eugene Russell on which he requests to have his membership discontinued (1966); Excerpt from Board Minutes of the committee's report, includes: a report on applicant Harry Galfand which was followed by his acceptance into the Academy, discussion of the issue of whether or not the Academy should take a stance on proposed legislation permitting employers to petition for an NLRB election, a special tribute to chairman Larry Seibel, the appointment of Rolf Valtin as the new committee chairman, a reimbursement authorized for the committee for expenses, the recommended admission of 13 applicants (all accepted but one for further review), the recommended rejection of 6 applicants, and a notification of the 7 applications still pending (1966); Sympathy letter to wife of deceased member Joseph Stashower (1966); Letters from new members thanking for their acceptance and noting the enclosed dues checks (1966); Letter from an applicant thanking for the mailing of the application materials and noting that he sent in the completed form (1966); Letter staffing the committee (1966); Letter arranging that the insurance material be sent to the new members (1966); Letter noting the death of member Joe Stashower (1966); Letter arranging for the printing of another Certificate of Membership since one of the first batch was incorrect due to an Academy mistake, also the original letter requesting the imprinting of the certificates (with the one mistake) (1966); Letter notifying the new members of their acceptance into the academy, and also serving as a cover letter for the usual materials: the Membership Directory, the Code of Ethics, the Constitution, etc. (1966); Letter noting the death of member Joe Stashower (1966); Cover letters to the application materials sent to applicants (1966); Letter to the membership urging them to consider paying a higher dues level since the Academy may run a deficit (1966); Letter suggesting that honorary member Cy Ching should not have to pay dues because of his honorary status, also suggests that the Board of Governor's meeting be moved up one week (1966) Letter transferring letters which concern the issue of applicants employed by state mediation boards, includes: a letter transferring these applicants' files, a letter sent to Academy members who are or were members of state mediation agencies to try and solicit their opinions about what the membership policy should be for applicants from these agencies, a letter from the president notifying a member that he will be in this member's town and will stop by to see him, letters from member Arvid Anderson and James Hill expressing their views on how these applicants should be handled, a letter from Arvid Anderson to the committee chairman thanking him for distributing the letter on state mediation boards to those Academy members who are or have been on such boards, letters from members who have been or are on state mediation boards relating their opinions on this issue, letter from Arvid Anderson clarifying a point in his policy letter regarding the review of decisions, (1965-1966); Letter inquiring as to the qualifications for membership in the Academy and the Academy's reply which serves as a cover letter to the "Statement of Policy Relative To Membership" (1966); Letter from secretary to several committee chairmen soliciting necessary information for the printing of stationary for each committee, also notifying them that they are entitled to reimbursement for mailing and telephone expenses (1966); Copy of the report of the committee to the Board of Governors, includes: a list of applicants recommended for acceptance, a list of the applicants recommended for rejection, and a list of the applicants who were deferred or whose applications are pending a decision (1966).